...will start.
Hello.
Welcome back from lunch.
Ladies and gentlemen and the millions of viewers...around the world.
My name is a claimants...and the lead architect for the agile
t services what that means is that when I say something in the team
then sometimes they listen to me?
And, I'll talk about after I...security and the to start with.
Let me tell you what book currently read every book that's was
...in nineteen eighty four.
that has been reissued in nineteen ninety nine called normal accidents?
And, it's really about the sociology of accidents that
happen complex systems which is really interesting it has to do with
io t because what we're doing here is we're building...start to
build very complex systems that are interacting with each other and where security?
Takes up new shapes and shapes that were not so
familiar with as an industry especially when I talk about the it industry.
You should see the score the session afterwards
you're going to see the barcode again to be entered into the daily prized drawing of something that's
sure surely fabulous...idea what is though.
All right.
So, I'm going to talk about the connected things in the io
...I'll give you a bit of aninventory of what we already know
practice is that we already know-how to do and,
then also and this is why this talk is not only for you in the room
who have made the time to come to build and to think that investing time in
coming to microsoft conferences a good idea but seriously the folks were going to what
...is later who probably don't even know yet that there are...audience also for them
is very interesting you'll know why I'll talk about some security and privacy
principles that were following
...were giving out as guidance as relates to the ot and I'll talk about the agile
t services and how they go and implement them and I'm also going to give you
some outlook and roadmap because we're really only at the beginning of a journey here and,
as an industry because the io
t currently at the top of the high site hype cycle and right now?
Most is written.
Not encode by...magazines and in marketing brochures.
We're going to get to the point where most
...written encode the number going to go and go down into that
...I got is really difficult phase.
Until we actually land on the ...of productivity.
When I talk about connected things or the...t this is a picture that kind of covers what I
mean...trying to be comprehensive so, we have
in personal environment's and networks we have watches glasses work
tools hearing aids robotic assistance by on aac systems?
They're really around people or in very small environment stuff that gets wired together.
Then we have those things kind of wired up to bigger systems.
And,...also...forget impersonal environment's and local
environments in these networks what you can also count towards that is local bus systems
are industrial automation...
Stuff that gets
...together can...then you have larger systems which are put together
from multiple devices
...vehicles...vessels factories farms all platforms.
Which have a local network
a vehicle today like the typical?
Upper-class luxury vehicle you can...
Has forty microprocessors in it micro
controllers in your key fob as a microcontroller...harks
via radio with your card that's already fairly complex system all put together on a...
Those
devices will speak to external increasingly speak to external systems.
This is these local systems exist and they have been evolving
for many years as closest...arguably some of the first io
t applications were built in at least
on what we know from the history record on this side of the iron curtain
by...the department of defense for the
purpose of detecting russian bombers within very version...time.
Which were very large computing systems?
That were plug together and they were effectively taking sensor data in
radar data in were correlating that...that data to detect within very short time with
...would be attacked...arguably the first I'll thesis those ever built and that already
had a notion of integrating data from different sites.
Into one
common information base and that's something that was built in the early sixties.
So, when I see column here I don't necessarily mean
...cloud...public cloud but also mean
cloud systems in general I mean datacenter systems you have local environments?
That communicate out to with centralize
data collection data analysis and control systems either directly through
...isp system or through...mobile network operator gateways...
So, that's when I say connect the things I mean?
Those systems and now the question is how do we go
and secure how we go-go about securing all those things now.
Let's think about how important the security is in here.
This is about io t enabled infrastructure.
What the picture I showed you previously is investor automation you can go and easily fit into that
...to get back to that and how you can go fit that into the picture but here you have enabled
infrastructure cities buildings energy health mobility traffic
Have health system lab equipments energy nuclear waste
management coal mining buildings signage?
Medical emergency systems.
And, all...systems which are vital to our communities...which are run
somehow today and they work what we want to do is want to use digital technology to make...
ever more efficient but that means that we're now creating more integration
more communication paths potentially more text surface obviously.
Which leads to...very important point?
Safety matters.
Security is a function of the overall safety strategy for systems.
In it security kind of is more or less the self-contained thing with the internet a
things becomes up...the whole story becomes up level the
...higher the highest priority thing is really safety many environment.
So, for a few sentences here many lt solutions control critical
...at the core of industrial and civil infrastructure.
So, the digital security will be increasingly interwoven with physical safety of life and equipment that's something
that's good that's driving the my boss has told me hey.
Since your the architect for those services the one thing I want to
...care of is one are security story
to right and that's something I have a lot of respect for because of this.
Because really it's not only
security story it's not an info sex story.
It's a safety story.
Many ot solutions will provide very deep in
near real-time into insight into industrial in business processes.
As well as into homes and the immediate personal
...privacy matters and one thing
we're very clear about in the across the entire platform specifically and
asher is that your data.
...you store your application data
in our platform is your data and we're going to
help you protected what you'll also find us do is to write up the guidance
in the principles that we've follow for our own services.
...how do we protect the data that is in let's say outlook dot com we have very strong
principles...how we think about privacy for
services that we build for customers that we go and
right those down and help people help developers who are building
coyote apps on top of our platform follow those principles if they want to
but the foundational principle that we have around privacy is your data is your data we're not going to
go...your service and then do analytics and
should know create value of that datalike others mites want to do?
When we already know we know a lot of things and now I want to go
...a type of person that we?
Are now starting to interact with which is a type of person who is kind of been on the other
...the fence in who are now getting to know
as it people?
It's the software people who are on the operational side hardware
...have so far been kind of mostly hardware designers
machine designers machine builders who've been seeing kind of software as a
little bit of additional group that needs to be done but who become increasingly
more software developers and now...and plug-in those things together...people I call
...operational technology engineers these are.
The real engineers if you will.
The people don't build software we call ourselves engineers but the people who have call themselves
engineers before we started to do that that's the people were me who have very
rigid procedures around a lot of stuff already around safety and there's
...and there's international standards as a lot of stuff that's happening on the safety
side that we can take a look at and that's the reason why I read the book and why
...not only that book but a ton of books is we can learn a lot from?
Literally decades of information decades of experience
around safety because we're now part of a context that is very
often safety driven with coyote solutions so it engineers we know-how to make a lot of
digital...secure which I'm going to go in and go through a little bit more detail secure development
lifecycle secure network technologies et cetera et cetera going to get to those ot
engineers no have standards procedures training
...improvement some people will say my god that's waterfall.
Yes, some of those things are waterfall.
Safety management and security management is a very rigid
thing.
For reason because you don't want to kill people.
So, there's
going to be culture clash between those two worlds of the software side where we want to do
angel and very quick and everything and on the operational
...and we see those culture clashes in all of the engages that were...like I'm not going to
update my software on the device and in fact windows xp.
What are the reasons why windows is so
still so popular in the investor automation spaces because?
It's still supported the imbedded version is still supported its operating system
was published what thirteen fourteen years ago now...own support.
I want to update my system that's a that's never change
running system that's something that's ingrained in the culture of
...operational technology and of course they have a notion of risk and hazard and nowand,
hazards that we really don't have any experience with...people.
We don't kill...we don't kill people with our stuff usually.
Microsoft has and has a number of cloud security principles...took this from a talk that?
More consider...at the rsa conference so we first we
protect
so these are capabilities that we built into the platform.
And, that we help you with security developed secure development site life-cycle network
...identity isolation that stuff that we do at the network at the network level these privilege
just-in-time access that's something how we do security containers vulnerabilities
and update management that's what we help with the platform and then we're
actually doing a ton of work for you and that's something for another
talked specifically about asher security all up in terms of...certification
I'm going to name a few standards...the end of the talk life's...penetration testing
where we're actually having our platform attacks at all times and we have
...out it's actually a handsome money that you can earn by just hacking
...platform in life production and, we have institute
...use the detection we have a digital crimes unit that's helping with digital
crimes helping things tracking things they'll
...bartlett's down we're having pretty sophisticated this
divert distributed denial of service defenses having a lot of stuff they're already doing kind of just at the
datacenter level...securing the platform as...infrastructure.
For applications for solutions but also for products.
One thing we have a secure development lifecycle the
secured available lifecycle something that has emerged out of microsoft's.
Bad days.
If you remember windows xp before windows xp sp...
Those were not very happy times because security was their security was arguably
...from the very beginning but it was not consistent there was not
a consistent process for how to apply security principles so
this the platform the core was okay the shell didn't care
much or not as much as they should and it was pretty on even across teams every team
could kind of kind of do its own applies on principles that stopped with the
security were set that was effectively started with windows xp sp to the
...secured...secure development lifecycle with effectively
...completely out of this which says first of all there's
a training requirement that everybody who participates in the process
...to have a minimal education around security and that's something that we live like at
...required security trainee for every engineered who touches code.
At microsoft so we have all have to go through this every year
...then on the requirements
...for any product or any software that you right you stab alicia what the security requirements are
with your baseline what is acceptable what is not acceptable based on
a once you've done that then you establish what the design requirements
are and then you have a rough sketch of what the architectures going to be and then you do
threat modeling which means you try to figure out what are the attack services if you have...application.
Right and then you make a call once you once, you know, what the potential threads...your
attack vectors are could be then you make a decision of which you want
to mitigate and how they what you want to mitigate them and sometimes you will choose not to mitigate some?
if you choose not to mitigate them some that is a documented act and
your explicit about it and that's something that matters.
If this looks like waterfall for...to you, yeah, that's wonderful.
But, that's okay.
Because with the next iteration you can come back to this so we're practicing this even in the a
job projects for doing that all the time and that's something and then you go into
...implementation use only approve tools only approved algorithms
there's
...md five is one of those hash algorithms that still very popular
and here is ...standard and there's a...still using md five microsoft we
can use eighty-five period for no purpose if we just need to have a hash.
Just the hash function to go and identify
something just a hash function to go and create hash table we can't use shot too.
Because it's unclear whether
would use it for security reasons so we have to use other hash
...we only need to have the for...secure purposes very strict about those things about
those procedures so all those things I'm not going to give you a whole talk
about the est-il you can get all that material from st elders actually qualify partners who can help you
establishing the dls something that is very useful to build secure
software and we believe also secure products we're currently doing is we're looking through the sd
...and see how much we can go and extend that to.
Makers and also to in dust to industrial product
folks what changes we need to make what augmentation...we need to make and
we're also very happy to get feedback on this.
What's also important...the kevin has in the previous talked, talked about this
is events in-depth...in-depth is something that we take very seriously
and all layers and also out's in all
...in all these different zone so there's the clouds zone...want to do what we go
and do defense in-depth on the datacenter side that starts with the physical
layer obviously getting into datacenter getting to a computer in one of
our datacenters is going to be not very happy experience?
If you are not authorized to do that I'm sure some will be in the way at some
point.
Then but even then one of the things we do kind of at the host
physical layer is we have stricter separation between the
sites and the suffer ones in it so I would not be able to tell which of the
machines run my were runs where workload that's something that we strictly separate out.
The rest defense in-depth we do in the cloud side there's...depth that we also help with in
on the device side so with windows ten also with windows
...with the current operating system and,
with a full operating system...a defense in-depth model it really starts download the hardware level
and allows you to have with the rtp...ship keys that are in the hardware than a
lot in the hardware and that then you have a trusted model we can have a secure
boot loader that's...by that pm that will then go
...the operating system that will then go and load only trusted components.
So, you can create the...can create the super secure systems that's the foundation having
...secure having secured or the defense in-depth basically taking measures
...all level of the system is the foundation for all the things that we do.
It all the things that we belief need to be done io t.
That's not all because there's the reality kinda gets in
the way sometimes the first thing is not all devices
are devices that are at the range where you can go and run
a full operating system with all security features
we have ten thousand-dollar servers on one side which are super easy to
defends and we have one dollar sensors on the other side that are basically just
a little microcontroller if you just take a look at the maker platforms because they're actually good
point reference the rest very pi is a full computer
and has ample capacity if you play with one of the lower lois and
...do we nodes?
That's.
That's about the capacity that might sinclair z is eighty-one have it's just much faster.
But, it's a huge range so you have
these super cheap sensors and the only way we're going to get to however trillion devices is
Read the next analyst thing...week...going to be some quadrant.
The only way how that's going to happen is that stuff is going to be fairly cheap so,
it's going to be one dol devices to that are devices and really when you think about and
this is what I say with that with the second bullet.
How much can you add to toaster?
you make a toaster and make a connected toaster instead of just make a plane toaster and you sell that post
...usually for thirty-nine ninety-five.
How much how much more expensive can the connect those derby?
Maybe, yeah, so, if you make ten bucks
then that is five dollars for the retailer right.
And, then that's two dollars for all the other people who want to go and,
make money on this so it's three.
And, then the actual bomb that you get allocated is probably a dollar-fifty.
That's what you gotta live with for the logic and the coach and the connect connectivity logic and
all those things that makes...hard so that constraints
...computational capabilities which means that also
...how much crypto you can do memory storage capacity,
capacity that also says how much logging for instance you can do how much
can you can keep track of things energy consumption.
...analysis services tech if you can if you can make a device who runs on...that runs on
battery just burn it's birds battery on senseless compute work.
And, then the component qualities also big factor.
A sensor.
That costs about our with connectivity logic.
...sensors you could buy the cost five.
And, ten fifty.
And, five hundred and five thousand.
Depending on the quality the lowest quality censor
...potentially break earlier the interesting thing is.
...sensor...a broken sensor.
...hard to distinguish.
It also becomes a data quality shoals so.
So, data quality can also gets looped into with the security...safety
so capability constraint devices is something that is a that's a that's a big concern.
Also not everything that we see is greenfield
right factories other industry utility environment's are all
...field production lines are getting upgraded
...tool but you don't go and build a whole new building except
for when you set up a new site than you do but otherwise you are using
reusing equipment and there's many environment's which have been upgraded for
...forty fifty years which keep get getting upgrade my favorite example because I'm a
Airplane gig is the...bfifty...
Which has now been flying for sixty years and the will
continue to fly until two thousand forty when they all this airplanes are going to be eighty-years-old?
they just keep...getting upgraded one by one by one by one of many factory...just like that.
So, you don't get to do a greenfield
brand-new install in many environments especially in a number comes to infrastructure
...and homes are like that too if you think about how you are introducing just in your house
introduce new technology you don't go to best buy and say I'd like to buy the
...the store no you go and biasing.
And, then three months later you go to buy another thing and then three months later you go with your wife and
she says null.
So, you wait another three months.
So, it's a it's a process that goes one by one by one and that also creates a lot of
diversity in your systems but it's also not a it's not ecosystem one-story
...security obviously comes out of this.
What we found very surprising is the legacy
network design attitude in specifically in industrial environment's industrial automation
environment's that's something that came as shouldn't have come as a surprise to
us when we were starting to look at this fromteam perspective two-and-a-half years ago but I
kinda was because as...people your now all kind of this expecting that
you have some level a some application-level security capabilities
...and endpoint here and endpoint there and they have a notion
of in identifying each other towards each other and we found?
In very many environment's none of that...very many environment that we
...investor automation as well as in manufacturing in as
...very many other environment's is that
because the ip folks?
Cutting-edge it folks have long been so self-absorbed with building all these wonderful social
experiences they haven't been really paying attention much to what has been
happening in those industrial environments as a consequence they've been just using best practices
of the off-the-shelf effectively to go...networks which you can't blame them
for and was what has happened is that they've...
Secure networks that mimic the
exact scenarios of how they secure the perimeter so they
built waltz and then in those...you can go and move freely.
And, then you build doors into those
systems gates that you can come through so we have a secure network and,
you can't get into that network networks isolated once you're in the network is actually fairly easy to
communicate with other parties and if you want to get in then you have a designed
door that design door looks often like this you can
buy security in the industry automation space in the form of
two black boxes.
From the number of vendors there's thousands and...vendors...sell
...these boxes which are effectively little
vp and bridges which have sometimes advertised hardware
see fit certificates which make them super secure...argument there is you so you...five
...certificate you put into the hardware and therefore the hardware is now certified to be secure.
That's nonsense but that's actually in the marketing
material so now you doing this.
Now you're actually setting up your network...is exif this
...existing practice you have this low the local error production network you have a
...motes service technician who wants to go and
...get at this with his workstation in some other place so they go and build this bridge.
What are the threads are
...mitigated or that exist in this right you have?
So, this is the...modeling model so...have spoof
in temporal repudiation information disclose...serves elevation of privilege.
And, I've done a little modeling of this model
where the communication path is subject to tampering and information disclosure
and now of service the machine control logic is actually
threatened by all those things the path to the configuration of the device is also
t id configuration itself is sub is potentially
subject repudiation the operator is also subject to spoof
...at repudiation so we were categoryauthenticate,
authenticate him or her so this kind the
threat model for that particular communication
length so those security devices what do they help with?
Not a whole lot what they help with is basically just tampering
information disclosure making the network secure but they're
not doing something that's actually very dangerous diffusing the networks.
Because
one network becomes part of the other network because there is no in vp n.
Vp...a network integration bridging technology there's no in vp and this
x is only about having a secure network cable that
you plugged in that one thing it's another thing that virtual network cable that the network cable is
virtual it runs over the internet but there's otherwise...security technology
it actually is worse because it enables that if you own the service this.
You can only machine.
Because with the attitude of not having endpoint level security.
That's a huge problem.
And, that's something that we fines in a lot of environment's a lot of legacy
...and there's also the way how
this stacks that worm that you may have heard of...
That didn't even need to have a vp
n gate a access that was it was enough to go infect use
...that was put into what are the service desks that then got owned
inside the factory which then stage a
pretty elaborate attack against those systems which were pretty wide open to access.
That was this was one of the moments where I had to close my eyes and basis leave the room
we've also seen this vehicle telematics so there are in vehicle telematics in this
...a commercial environment that exact same model so you have
trucks.
That dial-in that have a have a network connection over
three-g that effectively dial-up into vp and into viet vp and gateway into
one of two ways either through a private aps and that the mobile network operator
traits which is advertises peer-to-peer capable.
So, through that private a pm your career dialing into vp
...a vp n which is peer-to-peer cable which means the device can talk to each other.
And, but, we also have seen other variations of this where they go and the dial into
...into the...that's on-site so one of the to.
So, either they come through a public...or they go through private
aps and then once you own one of those equals.
I mean you own them
...sense right you hacker you get pretty.
Direct access to all the rest that's in the network.
And, that's pretty scary.
There's other issues with this so this is
...obviously security obviously a security risk.
There's more issues for instance so when you do this when you use
this lower-level effectively layer-two network integration
...technique to go in and integrate a truck.
With the cloud system and try to send data to the truck.
You have to stick with that networking technology right so you have to go
into the nesting.
...need to do the dhcp thing if you don't have static ip addresses.
Let's say you don't have to do that well then you still have the so you need to go and
find you to register the device.
And, then you also need to know if you want to send a message to truck and that's and that
...is currently not online because driving through tunnel or it's currently on a
ferry or whatever then you have to wait until the truck shows up again so there's
...poorer coupling that you creating by having everything being a network server but it
is really dangerous because now you...putting you putting devices that are of...operated
by different people and...are exposed to the environment into a single vp n.
Again, there's no in vp n.
Back to those sensors because let's go
more on the on the what was that the left side
of the continuum when it comes to prices?
Let's think about all the little gadgets and gives moves you can buy for the whole.
Let's think about five-dollar ten dollars whether
sensors sensor equipment that you put on
the side of buildings to know what the noise level with the pollution level what
the environmental conditions are throat a city.
Let's make those twenty bucks or fifty bucks but those devices all need to be needs to
be relatively cheap they'll be equipped with.
Small.
With small and low capability circuitry.
If you act if you actually operate them a servers they will have to go and triage
to traffic that comes in them they have to make a decision...whether they want got
what go let someone in or not if someone comes...attacks them.
...have to keep log because if you put...device or server out there and you
don't look into the log of whether someone attacks it well then eventually
...come if...to get in you have to look for this so how does...device which is
sitting somewhere...pinned against the wall people login whose look into that mode.
Will you go and...million tiny and...public, public network servers?
...do you think they could helps
...need some help with that we think they could need some help with that.
So, we have a principle there is nothing that we invented.
It's called services of communication
...a model where all devices that are in and
io t scenario which are the sm these small
devices that you find around the house the ones that are you know,
just adding a dollar or three or five to the
...materials how we can go and even reason about security
network which means we need to have a service and that service can either live on-the-field
gateway that's a device that you have around the house or in the facility which
can go and help out or it's a cloud service.
you have this you have an isolated network here isolated network can be anything
...effectively the pam that you have in the initial slide or the local network that I
on the initial slide it can be anything from a mobile operator network
sell to a to in all the local home network.
And, there's going to be a router at the edge.
Let's establish first one thing.
has been said and it's there's plenty of articles you can read.
This more being more written in were in
...then there's written...code there's.
Plenty article signal read that say we must have ip vsix
because we're going to have ten billion devices and every one of those devices
...to have a public ip address that ladies and gentlemen is complete nonsense it
is complete nonsense because count all the devices that you have
...your own homes and your geeks which means you're going to have player those.
Which have a public...ip address?
Adventures here you have five well...professor.
It's not a lot.
It's your gateway...router and
nat is not a bad idea at all...actually good idea because it keeps the networks
it keeps...network separate your devices that you have and the extra even if you bring in
extra new device in your home or even if you bring in extra new device in the in...for into
...production environment.
The presence of that device doesn't change the foundational design if
your network which isn't expecting that anybody shows up to visit
...the lower network layers so having that network address translation haven't
that the separation between those networks is a healthy thing to have and I think that's also something
was worth preserving.
Who needs ip six other people who are building these
mobile base stations because that's going to explode?
And, mobile base stations not only as traditional mobile network operators but also things like
...fox which is a french company...building a is mba
...embed base networks where you can but by a data plan that gives you
fifty messages per or...messages per day which each
half like sixteen bytes but that's enough if you want to build a connected cal?
No, kidding no kidding you can
...for second series business connected...
If you want to know when that cou when that cou is ready to have babies that's an
...to figure out also you just general generally if you have a very large from you want to know whether
you're cows are live is still living or whether somewhere out there.
And, that's something you can do with the service like this very nicely so all of those things are connected to
these router so the way how this works is very simple any device goes...out through
gateway to a service gateway that service gateway has a bucket that's
...so that device the devices period with that service gateway which means
educate taints it has one credential and it knows one
peer that will communicate with ever.
It doesn't need to have a local of a local
authentication database it doesn't need to have any of those things it only needs to know that one key
that of the party that...truss and...to have a key to identify itself and a second key to
role then we'll go and creative stable connection out
to that service gateway whenever it sees the network.
To send messages to the device you go and
stop-and-go from the client decent data to the service gateway to a name and not
to...address which very nicely solves the problem of a car.
...driving along a road fast.
On the...we don't have these crazy researchers that you people have here so,
I go with normal cruising speed that whole like hundred-miles-an-hour I
ate switch cell towers about every minute so every
one-and-a-half minutes help between cell towers specifically on the hire band on the
hire throughput bands which means also get a new address at each of
those which means am inconvenient to reach
...to get the timing right because I'll be switching networks and,
also a be difficult to address if I get a local address there this year this model is solving that very
nicely but having a stable name and whenever I reconnect effectively I just
go and pull...messages for me from that service gateway and
then sending in I'm sending through that gateway that
gateway again might be local so it might be a local gateway
...you have in the house or it might be a
...gateway of the sort...building.
The device does not listen...traffic all connections are device initiated
and outbound...mappings automatic and outbound.
And, now in blog ports open the...services minimize your house is safe.
That's the other crazy thing right if you have up and pe
support on your wireless lan router and have that turned on?
You crazy.
The scenario we see people asking for all the time is.
I want to control my a
insert device here washer dryer car.
With my cell phone.
Or my galaxy.
So, how do you realize that well you go through the same model?
You don't need to have local peering but you go through a
service gateway or you will goal and that's even more likely throw mobile back-end you
connected device up to that service gateway that's where gets nailed up
right and then you come from the mobile device go through the mobile app or go
straight through the to the service gateway if you have to necessary...and sent the message that way.
So, let's say you want to go and build is solution for car sharing and for car
sharing where you can go and the say hey I need to have a car that I want to go
and drive and I'm going to get itwant to get the...
Seconds later the app says hey, yeah, I have a car for
you the car is over there over there over there and then it's the white one and,
just walk up to it so I woke up to it on the app I can
...push a button car unlocks.
Magic.
What the authorization for that act of unlocking the car is something that
will have to be brokered by the system either?
...by phone some information to
have a local connectivity but that's something that would depend on certain radio capabilities
in my phone or it does the remote unlocked directly when I push a button and that would
then come through that path where the mobile back-end is effectively employee authorization logic.
But, it's a very elegant solution to
avoid all of the local networking setup stuff because everybody can...of...a single place.
And,...is secure.
Because both parties have appeared connection with the...
And, you get to poured coupling of it.
Further thing that's also part of this services communication model
is trust brokerage for nomadic devices the currents the current models for vehicle to
vehicle and vehicle to infrastructure a standards...iso standards
Call effective for the for creating the largest pk isis them in the world.
Where effectively every car gets certificate
...those certificates are manage at massive scale and we're going to be ending up with the
system that will go and distribute and role and replace certificates at the scale of several?
Billion vehicles eventually.
And, also will go and distribute the net the necessary certificate
...lists which are going to be funny because, you know,
stuff gets stolen stuff good stuff breaks et cetera et cetera so we're also going to have city of your
revelation replication list of kind of the same dimensions that it's not going to work.
We have mechanisms to deal with that and mechanisms like.
Having a devices...device identity system and
...token system that allows to do this right so
I trust as a device that registry the other device also
trust that registry and which means now a device can ask for token that
are under another device can actually ...being trustworthy
...token can be varied in lifetime and that's something that's
a very useful model for enabling peer-to-peer communication which will be
is essential because if you driving along the street?
you need to have information from the infrastructure what you're what you're traffic lights are doing or what
your...are doing you can't rely on call connectivity which means local radio
something that's important but we can't do is we can't have this huge pk infrastructure with trying-to
...starts etc we need to have something is lighter-weight and having that
...brokered trust model where you have
tokens with a limited lifetime which you can go and requires something that's actually more feasible?
So, all the translated into vehicle telematics from the previous picture
This is something that we do.
Today with all give you name.
There a commercial truck company.
And, they have
an inc up bridge in their telematics box and that telematics
box is talking through to answer using the impure peeling that
is the only solution that does that we have another solution that that's from the
alfie tool fob that you can...plug-in your car that's also using
the same principle and we have a number of other solutions that do that in vehicle
telematics another set of manufactures I can't name.
If...http...link its bidirectional
...by default reliable transfer application-level and
no exposure to the tiers they...sitting on the same network
right there's no integration at the lowest-level
...we just all application-level integration.
Industrial automation were working very closely I'm actually sitting I'm sitting on the
opec foundations of the techniques advisory council and also a member of the
opie cu a working group.
Which is a consortium four hundred sixty companies
mostly all from the operational technology side industrial automation where
creating standards for industrial automation integration and opie see way?
...something has to build kind-of for making creating compatibility creating integration
...the factory floor realizing.
That security's important opus your
usa already implements point-to-point security.
But, that doesn't change the fact that the factory floor per
say is not necessarily secure so the model were putting into opec way for the
working group level is a model where you have the notion of an opie
see way gateway and then later...us also putting this into the opie
servers so that the cloud link is
...is done through exactly the same principle all outbound
status stable connection and that's how the routing happens so...we see way or
ds or any other protocol that's being used inside and then having
effectively a gateway that facilitates the communication with.
Demonstrate this
...hanover...with a number of companiesthe
...devices speaker some see labs that's a company in seattle
that's building investor automation solution and they have build a bridge between opie
...and the cloud that you can actually buy as a device or the software from
see labs to make...integration happen...doing the working group...kind of formalizing that link.
For that sort of integrations so that we can go from environment which has not been
designed for being exposed to the cloud it can go
into very securely link this with environments that are in the
column that also brings all the reliability capabilities with
that because and opie see way environment my
quite well be sitting on a truck and moving or sitting on a ship and moving.
Another massive, massive issue.
If we think about these vehicle solutions.
We're talking about devices
we're talking about management of devices at the scale of millions if
we're building this into a into the standard as a stellar capability into
...your quickly at a million two million three million vehicles output
out of a single brand per year.
That's a lot.
If you think about how the biggest how big the biggest active directory deployment is that,
you know.
Magnitudes away from that.
So, you have to have...actually goes deals with that in the and it also
can do software update management which is importance at that scale.
And, just to illustrate.
A million.
Is a lot right?
So, what we have as makers
...in a heck...like hundreds of devices enterprise
...proud of...ten thousands of devices?
Consumer products is millions of devices.
So, that's something that call for additional infrastructure that to deal with the
security so...we're building is part of the ire address ut
...a piece that sits in the after I ot suite which is the delegated
component specifically aiming to solve the scale issues
...specifically the security issues so I don't
see how job as part of the io t
...provides effectively a model for creating.
Millions of devices up to ten million devices per
...for I'll see how this curly the goal that we have.
With explicit support for
feel gateways explicit support for additional protocol.
As a service solution that you can be that you'll be able to
build to effectively go to the after poorly
crater coyote hub and you're going to get this bidirectional capability
that bidirectional capability will give you a way to go and talk directly with
...hub using https.
One point one or two.
Or with aim compete and explicit about the here.
And, we'll also give you a way and this is something we're going to provide as a self host book
capability to talk in...tt as capability and that gateway will also
be the foundation that you can go and build on if you want to support further protocol
...going to go and extend to further protocols as well the way you
can think of coyote hub is that it is a super.
Charge bidirectional version of events
hub with further capabilities so it's building on the foundational scale
...ub which can today already do.
A million sources and over one gigabyte per second throughput we're
currently doing on events ub over fifteen billion messages per day.
So, on that capability.
Were building up the io
...hub on that phone on that on that skill foundation were actually extending that even.
For services connectivity you going to have these per device command
...so let me go through this quickly so hyper
...identity registry in there so that you can have millions of
these devices indeo...registered so we're going to allow you to go and register them
and will also be able to federated identity with active directory?
We're going to be secure by principle.
At the main gateway of the
...hub you will not be able to use protocols that are not secure.
We will not allow...http traffic if you want
...plane...should be traffic you can do that but you have to go and make itself also gateway.
We will support initially tls with the starts.
We will then also extend this to also support
...ps k which shaved off the certificate
exchange and allows you to operate with shared keys on both sides
of the connection which makes the exchange much quicker and much more lighter-weight
in specifically designed for that purpose will also look into using tls...pk which is
...public key which does the same thing with asymmetric
...cryptography and there's specifically interesting for super bandwidth constraint links
so if you paying your mtwo m connection by the kilobytes
...always sending five
kilobytes starts across the wires not a good idea if it's always the same thing and,
...typically because the peering is strong because...have of gateway in advice you don't need the
search you actually don't want to have the third-party certificate authority in the middle having a key exchange
actually sufficient and, we're going to have effectively native support for the services the communication model just talked about.
You will generally authenticate at the channel level so whatever that
channel is...http et-cetera and, then authenticate
...and...authorized against the gateway based on that device registry there's also going
to be a blacklist for tokens and then all the messages are coming in there are tag
by us with the identity of that device so that is something that the device
can't spoof.
The device can't say I'm sending I'm the device so-and-so which you can curly do
right today you can say I'm device so-and-so but you have to go prove that you device
...we're actually stamping that on based on the authentication results.
And, then also we're going to add is device
...foundation so that you can do software updates through
that system that you can go and get the state of your devices through that system and software
...something that is obviously super important if you want to...secure processes.
So, last three minutes let me speculate about the future a little bit.
There's a lot io t challenges I already talked about some of them right
there's cost pressure...device hardware cheap sensors weak or
no crypto the source of randomness if you need to if you want to crypto you
have to start with some random numbers...random numbers of a super tiny chip it's kinda hard.
Time management is...
Just the fact of not having a real time clock in a super cheap device try to do that
...dwindle good luck there's an analog gap.
With...of
audio the rm has kind of failed and the reason why the rm has failed is because it's
kinda hard it's kind of easy to go and play it back and recorded back with very minimal fidelity
analog gap also exists on the other side because you can go in degrade a
...you can cheat on a...right you have a temperature sensor new hold...lighter in front of it.
There's all kinds of a you can do physical hacks against digital systems...the digital systems
...cope with them especially not if they're cheap investor great
...can deal with them because they have defenses against that and they can go
and spot those things but cheap sensors can't.
So, what that means is that the defense in-depth is often broken
kind of at the lowest levels at the device in the field
gateway layer also because there's legacy?
There's a lot of stuff that will have to deal with which just
can't which we won't be able to secure because thirty-years-old so we already have
...services...we have we have machine identity
and axes authorization that we can do architecturally and that we're covering.
Further out.
Stuff we're also going to tackle is
...data stream authorization we're going to take a look at the data streams
and actually we figure out who's product we have to go and figure out
who's authorize to get that data and process that data in collaborative
environment's like factory we'll have to go and figure out what's the possibility of that data is
the sensor bad and integrate data quality concerns
with these with these authorization concerns...sensor and a broken sensor
are indistinguishable so data quality something that is part of the platform that we think we
can provide help with that also for privacy if you take the
rental car scenario you have rent-a-car you rent-a-car.
You sit
in it you drive two weeks later you call the rental car companies say...delete my data.
What the readily our company has legitimate rights to collect the
information from the vehicle so it's gotta be a way to attach your identity
from to that system and then remove your identity from that is secure way there's
...with how do we deal with privacy how do we deal with data quality how do
we deal with trust in those environments and
really also can have this that safety notion kind of flow into the system?
So, I'll to security is a shared responsibility security
concepts to the edge.
You should and implement the security developments lifecycle you can get help from us
this cyber security experts at microsoft can actually help with that leverage industry
best practices and then there's a lot of stuff that we do already you can start with the asher
ot...the services we have already events up is a great star the reference
...a great start and then I would also ask you to review a platform principles
and certifications because they're really part of that process we have a lot of...already making huge investments
and we're extending those even further and
without thank you very much for.
Spending that time with us and hope that was somewhat lightning a good conference.